<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Basics on Captus documentation</title>
    <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/basics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Basics on Captus documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/basics/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/basics/overview/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Captus, a toolkit for the assembly of phylogenomic datasets (many samples and loci) from High-Throughput Sequencing (a.k.a. Next Generation Sequencing) data. Captus was initially designed specifically for the assembly of target-enriched (e.g. via hybridization of RNA or DNA probes) sequencing data, but has since been expanded to accomodate other common types of HTS data such as Genome Skimming, Hyb-Seq (Target Enrichment + Genome Skimming), RNA-seq, and Whole Genome Sequencing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/basics/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/basics/installation/</guid>
      <description>The easy way (recommended) The simplest way to install Captus is to create an isolated software environment using conda, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have conda we recommend to install miniconda from https://docs.conda.io/en/latest/miniconda.html. Once you have conda installed in your system you need to configure your channels:
conda config --prepend channels bioconda conda config --prepend channels conda-forge conda config --show channels The last command should show your current channels, the order matters:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parallelization</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/basics/parallelization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/basics/parallelization/</guid>
      <description>(and other common options)  Throughout Captus&amp;rsquo; modules we provide common options that allow you limit the computer&amp;rsquo;s resources available to Captus, change the way of running parallel tasks, and control the amount of text shown during a run:
--ram With this option you can specify the maximum RAM in GB that Captus is allowed to use. For example, if your system has 64 GB of RAM and you want to limit the use to 32.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>