<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Align on Captus documentation</title>
    <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Align on Captus documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Options</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/options/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/options/index.html</guid>
      <description>align To show all available options and their default values you can type in your terminal:
captus_assembly align --help Input -e, --captus_extractions_dir Path to the output directory from the extract command, (e.g. 03_extractions iy you used the default name). The align command depends entirely on the output from the extract step, in other words, you can&amp;rsquo;t provide your unaligned or aligned FASTA files for processing.
This argument is required , the default is .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Output Files</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/output/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/output/index.html</guid>
      <description>For this example we will use the directory 03_extractions previously created with the extract module. We run the following Captus command to collect markers across samples and align them:
captus_assembly align align -e 03_extractions_CAP/ -o 04_alignments_CAP -m ALL -f ALL After the run is finished we should see a new directory called 04_alignments with the following structure and files:
Complete structure of the alignment output directory 1. 01_unaligned This directory contains the unaligned FASTA files corresponding to each marker that were gathered from the extractions directory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML Report</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/report/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/report/index.html</guid>
      <description>Concept This align module generates several sets of alignments that are ready-to-use in popular phylogenetic tree inference programs (e.g., IQ-TREE, RAxML, ASTRAL). Each alignment set differs from one another in the following four respects: 1) whether they are trimmed, 2) which paralog filter is applied, 3) whether they contain reference sequences, and 4) in which formats . Thus, it is important to understand the differences between each alignment set and carefully evaluate their quality in order to decide which alignment set to use for subsequent analyses.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>