<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assembly on Captus documentation</title>
    <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assembly on Captus documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clean</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/clean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/clean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unless you are starting with your own assemblies, cleaning will be the first step in the analysis. &lt;code&gt;Captus&lt;/code&gt; makes it easy to process many samples in a consistent manner, automatically, and providing a comprehensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/clean/report/&#34;&gt;Quality Control HTML report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Captus&lt;/code&gt; allows you the flexibility to provide reads cleaned elsewhere. however, we recommend our cleaning method for its accuracy in removing adaptors, which in turn improves the chances of getting a higher quality assembly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assemble</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/assemble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/assemble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next step in the workflow is to perform &lt;em&gt;de novo&lt;/em&gt; assembly with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/voutcn/megahit&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;MEGAHIT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the cleaned reads. Once the reads have been assembled into contigs, depth of coverage is calculated using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/COMBINE-lab/salmon&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Salmon&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;code&gt;Captus&lt;/code&gt; makes it easy to process many samples in a consistent manner, automatically, and providing a comprehensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/assemble/report/&#34;&gt;Assembly Control HTML report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;MEGAHIT&lt;/code&gt; is an extremely fast and robust &lt;em&gt;de novo&lt;/em&gt; assembler that is very memory-efficient thanks to the use of a new data structure called succint De Bruijn Graph (sDBG). Most importantly, accuracy is not sacrificed because it was originally designed for assembling metagenomes. Since then, it has been shown to be an excellent generalist assembler as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extract</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/extract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/extract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next step in the workflow is to search markers within the assemblies and extract them. For that you need to provide &lt;code&gt;Captus&lt;/code&gt; reference sequence(s) of the marker(s) you want to extract. You can provide coding sequences in either nucleotide or aminoacid, in this case, protein extraction will be performed with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webscipio.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Scipio&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. One key advantage of &lt;code&gt;Scipio&lt;/code&gt; is its ability of reconstructing gene models (i.e., exons + introns) from separate contigs in highly fragmented assemblies, which are not uncommon when analyzing hybridization capture or genome skimming data.&lt;br&gt;
If you want to extract any other DNA marker (entire genes with introns, ribosomal genes, non-coding regions, RAD reference loci, etc.) you provide your reference(s) in nucleotide format, in this case the extraction is performed using
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hgdownload.soe.ucsc.edu/admin/exe/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;BLAT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and our own code to stitch and extract partial hits if necessary in an analogous fashion to &lt;code&gt;Scipio&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s method.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Align</title>
      <link>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edgardomortiz.github.io/captus.docs/assembly/align/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last step in the &lt;code&gt;Captus&lt;/code&gt; workflow is to align the extracted markers so you can estimate phylogenetic trees with your favorite tool (e.g., &lt;code&gt;IQ-TREE&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;RAxML&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;MrBayes&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;SVDQuartets&lt;/code&gt;, etc.).
&lt;code&gt;Captus&lt;/code&gt; starts this step by gathering all the markers across your extracted samples and building a FASTA file per marker. Then, it will add the references used during extraction, these are useful to improve alignment since they serve as guides. Then &lt;code&gt;Captus&lt;/code&gt; aligns the files using &lt;code&gt;MAFFT&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;MUSCLE&lt;/code&gt;, however, if you choose to align coding sequence in aminoacid (&lt;code&gt;AA&lt;/code&gt;) and nucleotide (&lt;code&gt;NT&lt;/code&gt;) in the same run, &lt;code&gt;Captus&lt;/code&gt; will first align the &lt;code&gt;AA&lt;/code&gt; version with &lt;code&gt;MAFFT&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;MUSCLE&lt;/code&gt; and then use that alignment as template to align the &lt;code&gt;NT&lt;/code&gt; version, thus producing an codon-aware alignment of the coding sequence in nucleotides. Once alignment is completed, paralogs are filtered. Finally, during the trimming stage, Captus removes erroneous stretches of aligned sequences using &lt;code&gt;TAPER&lt;/code&gt; and then the gappy columns are removed with &lt;code&gt;ClipKIT&lt;/code&gt; (but you can any other &lt;code&gt;ClipKIT&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s filtering strategy) as well as exceptionally short sequences which tend to decrease phylogenetic accuracy.
At the end, &lt;code&gt;Captus&lt;/code&gt; provides several alignment formats from which you can choose the most appropriate for your needs as well as a comprehensive HTML report summarizing alignment statistics along the multiple stages of the &lt;code&gt;align&lt;/code&gt; step.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>